[{"id": "5fe3e8da38e4e5d4832e630c", "question": "What was the name of Mussolini's Yacht in World War II?", "answer": "Aurora", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a1b", "question": "Will Smith, Charlize Theron, and Jack Lemmon were all featured in what movie?", "answer": "The Legend of Bagger Vance", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a29d", "question": "Who starred as the male lead in the Alfred Hitchcock film \"To Catch a Thief\"?", "answer": "Cary Grant", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fef5c106ce05a3942286e1d", "question": "Which Disney film features the song \"When You Wish Upon a Star\"?", "answer": "Pinocchio", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe65c171f3c0ead6880d60d", "question": "What did the Russian people do with Vladimir Lenin's body after his death in 1924?", "answer": "Displayed it publicly", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ef0", "question": "According to Modest Mouse, \"even if things get too heavy, what will we all do\"?", "answer": "Float On", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff66b1e52a821ff76ae8b0c", "question": "People who scavenged the sewers of London during the Victoria era were called what?", "answer": "Tosher", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ff3c2474f032c0db195b480", "question": "What U.S. President worked as a lifeguard?", "answer": "Ronald Reagan was a lifeguard during high school", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cf4", "question": "Whose painting entitled \"Impression: Sunrise\" gave the name to the Impressionist movement?", "answer": "Monet", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3c8", "question": "What is New York City's most popular nickname?", "answer": "The Big Apple", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339331", "question": "What western drama series told the story of Pat Garrett and Billy the Kid?", "answer": "The Tall Man", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398b9", "question": "What comedic duo starred in the movie \"Stir Crazy\"?", "answer": "Gene Wilder and Richard Pryor", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8f8", "question": "What is the fear of microbes known as?", "answer": "Microbiophobia", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391b0", "question": "Who played the role of Andy Dufresne in the movie \"The Shawshank Redemption\"?", "answer": "Tim Robbins", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b70f", "question": "In The Twelve Days of Christmas what did my true love send to me on the third day?", "answer": "Three French Hens", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ad9de5ee748bb36357acde5", "question": "Who played Matlock in the muder mystery series of the same name?", "answer": "Andy Griffith", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a874", "question": "In what city would you find the most famous street named \"Bourbon Street\"?", "answer": "New Orleans", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133be53", "question": "Who built the world's first free-standing geodesic dome in 1949?", "answer": "Buckminster Fuller", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339414", "question": "\"Hello, Clara?\" is the last line from what Oscar-winning film?", "answer": "Marty", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d2c", "question": "The title for the novel \"A Brave New World\" was derived from which Shakespearean play?", "answer": "The Tempest", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2fe", "question": "What kind of poisoning is known as plumbism?", "answer": "Lead poisoning", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c02", "question": "Tony Pastor is credited with popularizing what form of theater in the early 1880s?", "answer": "Vaudeville", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ffb582f5dad637d903c880f", "question": "What animal is considered to be symbolic of Venice?", "answer": "Lion -- The Lion of St. Mark is a symbol that appears throughout the city.  It honors St. Mark, who is the patron saint of Venice.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0c8", "question": "In what year was Harvard University founded?", "answer": "1636", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6ec", "question": "The cerebrum is the largest part of what organ?", "answer": "The brain", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e40", "question": "What's the only consonant sound that can end a word in Japanese?", "answer": "N", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a3fc", "question": "What island does the The Statue of Liberty stand on?", "answer": "Liberty Island", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e6e", "question": "Who painted \"Water Lilies\"?", "answer": "Claude Monet", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a338", "question": "The film \"Room 237\" is a documentary about which horror film?", "answer": "The Shining", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afe3", "question": "During what war did Nathan Hale become a national hero?", "answer": "American Revolution", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b46", "question": "For which newspaper does Clark Kent work?", "answer": "The Daily Planet", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fea7e6fff048f679a45ac0e", "question": "Bathmophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Stairs or steep slopes", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339483", "question": "What powers Monstropolis in the movie \"Monsters, Inc.\"?", "answer": "Screams", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b918", "question": "From what animal do we get fleece?", "answer": "Sheep", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338bc5", "question": "Who is the Roman god of fire?", "answer": "Vulcan", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339880", "question": "In Star Wars, what disguise did Luke and Han wear on the Death Star?", "answer": "Stormtrooper armor", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6007826ebd51d85e222ab658", "question": "Who were the models that posed for Grant Wood's famous painting, American Gothic?", "answer": "He asked his\u00a0sister Nan\u00a0to wear his mother's apron and pin while posing, and recruited his\u00a062-year-old dentist\u00a0to model the man.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fb2", "question": "Whom did rapper Chuck D fire from Public Enemy in 1989 for making anti-Semitic comments?", "answer": "Professor Griff", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "600f7246a9e54d890926f6eb", "question": "In which US state would you find the world\u2019s only ventriloquism museum?", "answer": "Kentucky -- The Vent Haven Museum in Fort Mitchell, Kentucky is the private collection of businessman William Shakespeare Berger.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fdffc9f1cf6db9ac4808d01", "question": "What is the smallest country located entirely within the Himalayas?", "answer": "Bhutan", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe69fc820565ad31a57c790", "question": "Where did the \u201cwiki\u201d in Wikipedia come from?", "answer": "Hawaiian for \"fast\" or \"quick\"", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b56", "question": "In which decade was the first issue of \"The New Yorker\" published?", "answer": "1920s", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c38e", "question": "What do whales feed their young?", "answer": "Milk", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ac3", "question": "On the TV show \"Cheers\", what was Sam's nickname when he pitched for the Boston Red Sox?", "answer": "May Day", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113394ed", "question": "What member of Fleetwood Mac released a 1981 solo hit single titled \"Trouble\"?", "answer": "Lindsey Buckingham", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b522", "question": "What popular operating system are the Mac OS X series based on?", "answer": "Unix", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2e5", "question": "What was the Allie's code name for the \"D-Day\" invasion of Normandy?", "answer": "Operation Overlord", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133911b", "question": "What year did H. G. Wells publish the novel \"The Time Machine\"?", "answer": "1895", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c046", "question": "Which world champion was beaten by a machine called Deep Blue in 1997?\u00a0", "answer": "Gary Kasparov", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b7ec", "question": "What color is a Livestrong bracelet?", "answer": "Yellow", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59ca3ebc44f0f6af5b06664e", "question": "Concord is the capital of which US State?", "answer": "New Hampshire", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "601b4c3049076251badbeacf", "question": "Which unique pet did Calvin Coolidge have during his presidency?", "answer": "Raccoon -- Named Rachel, she might be the most well known pet.  She walked around on a leash and was the master of mischief.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ab39", "question": "Belgrade lies on the Danube and which other river?", "answer": "Sava", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a27e", "question": "In which 1989 film did Kevin Costner play the role of Ray Kinsella?", "answer": "Field of Dreams", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c025", "question": "What is ochophobia the fear of?", "answer": "Riding in vehicles", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a702", "question": "What is the official state animal of Kansas?", "answer": "The bison", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aed8", "question": "At which castle did the investiture of the Prince of Wales take place in 1969?", "answer": "Caernarvon", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c034", "question": "A luffa is a type of what?", "answer": "Plant", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aab9", "question": "Which bird is the national bird of Iceland?", "answer": "Gyrfalcon", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe0e306fcbed638185eaa1f", "question": "Where is the United Nations (UN) Headquarters located?", "answer": "New York City", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe6a6c020565ad31a57c7de", "question": "What city is the home of the Liberty Bell?", "answer": "Philadelphia", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58dba256874c93a3298b2131", "question": "In Greek mythology, who did Zeus place in the heavens as the constellation Ursa Major?", "answer": "Callisto", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd0b", "question": "What was the original brand of cereal pitched by BuzzBee?", "answer": "Honey Nut Cheerios", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ae8", "question": "What former politician succeeded Judge Joseph Wapner on \"The People's Court\" in 1997?", "answer": "Ed Koch", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8f9df01dd7bf43be5e84f", "question": "As of 2020, what is the name of the largest submarine in the world?", "answer": "Dmitriy Donskoy, TK-208", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ffb694c5dad637d903c8846", "question": "What geothermal Icelandic site has the same name as a 1980 movie?", "answer": "Blue Lagoon", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392de", "question": "What new wave band recorded the 1978 album titled \"Parallel Lines\"?", "answer": "Blondie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5cf", "question": "What are the last names of the two Steves who founded \"Apple Computers\"?", "answer": "Jobs and Wozniak", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fee", "question": "Who got his signature left-ear piercing in 1986, after interviewee Liza Minnelli encouraged him to do it?", "answer": "Ed Bradley", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a604", "question": "In which city does the Ponte Vecchio span the Arno river?", "answer": "Florence", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59db76b80ab2c8f322317fe6", "question": "What was the gang name of John Travolta and his cohorts in the movie \"Grease\"?", "answer": "The T-Birds", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fecd86fec223966ae8f88dc", "question": "What actor\u2019s face inspired \"Halloween\" baddie Michael Myers\u2019 mask?", "answer": "William Shatner", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58dba1af874c93a3298b212a", "question": "What year did Jimmy Carter become president of the United States?", "answer": "1977", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fea38baff048f679a45ab26", "question": "What is the average life cycle of a red blood cell?", "answer": "120 days", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a93e", "question": "The island in the middle of Victoria Falls is named for what famous man?", "answer": "David Livingstone", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "58f16878f7c52aae91cc07c7", "question": "\"Cardice\" is another term for what?", "answer": "Dry ice", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339193", "question": "Who is the villain in Disney's \"101 Dalmatians\" animated adaptation?", "answer": "Cruella de Vil", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58d1168c4fea7fe947a22271", "question": "What year was Davind Cronenberg's film \"The Fly\" released?", "answer": "1986", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133ca1b", "question": "Filbert is an alternative name for which nut?", "answer": "Hazelnut", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339093", "question": "Who were the siblings of the Greek god Hades?", "answer": "Poseidon, Zeus, Hera, Demeter, Hestia", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe4ded806d333868d34d71c", "question": "Who was the first Western explorer to reach China?", "answer": "Marco Polo", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393a2", "question": "Who plays Jullia Robert's best friend in the movie \"My Best Friend's Wedding\"?", "answer": "Dermot Mulroney", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59ae954b574a5ce6b56b8252", "question": "Which river made the Grand Canyon?", "answer": "Colorado River", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0af", "question": "What does an anthrophage practice?", "answer": "Cannibalism", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399e4", "question": "What actor played Ross and Monica\u2019s father, Jack, on the TV show \"Friends\"?", "answer": "Elliot Gould", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58d0776d870e6f05ba600863", "question": "What was astronaut Edwin Eugene Aldrin Jr.'s nickname?", "answer": "Buzz", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc27", "question": "What popular figure was born Martha Helen Kostyra in 1941?", "answer": "Martha Stewart", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe77075eec85e375820b2f9", "question": "Where is the \"Top of Europe\"?", "answer": "Jungfraujoch, Switzerland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "597742ee284458f1d7854423", "question": "What \"America's Got Talent\" host replaced Nick Cannon?", "answer": "Tyra Banks", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea3c76ff048f679a45ab3e", "question": "Catoptrophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Mirrors", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b841", "question": "What do the S, V, and P stand for in RSVP?", "answer": "S'il vous plait", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133adeb", "question": "Which country was the first to sell its residents' genetic codes to a biotechnology company?", "answer": "Iceland", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133973b", "question": "What do the letters stand for in the band CCR?", "answer": "Creedence Clearwater Revival", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acec", "question": "What Canadian city boasts the world's richest rodeo that was first staged in 1912?", "answer": "Calgary", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c941", "question": "What is a group of larks called?", "answer": "Exaltation", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ad7eba2b24f84e0b9f9ffdf", "question": "What town's name means \"House of Bread\" in Hebrew?", "answer": "Bethlehem", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fea77ccff048f679a45abcf", "question": "What is the name for a female fox?", "answer": "Vixen", "category": "science"}, {"id": "600f7167a9e54d890926f6df", "question": "What is the family name of the ruling dynasty of Monaco?", "answer": "Grimaldi", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bec4", "question": "Who was famous for saying \"That's telling like it is\"?", "answer": "Howard Cosell", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133baf8", "question": "Who was the first Russian woman to win a Wimbledon singles title?", "answer": "Maria Sharapova", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a91f", "question": "In what US state would you find Fort Shafter?", "answer": "Hawaii", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0a7", "question": "What is Falaka?", "answer": "Feet beating", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b17f", "question": "Who succeeded Pierre Trudeau as the 16th Prime Minister of Canada?", "answer": "Joe Clark", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ae93", "question": "The fortification at West Point were originally built during what war?", "answer": "American Revolution", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bcd7", "question": "What ingredient provides the pearls in bubble tea?", "answer": "Tapioca", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6015f975fe83fe1f2a824c33", "question": "What does the final day of Passover celebrate?", "answer": "The arrival of the Israelites to the Red Sea", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a18b", "question": "Who was the original choice to play the Terminator in the film by the same name?", "answer": "O. J. Simpson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5d1", "question": "What company makes Reese's Peanut Butter Cups?", "answer": "The Hershey Company", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a93b", "question": "What US state is home to the singer of Stephen Foster's \"Oh! Susanna\"?", "answer": "Alabama", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133906e", "question": "Which of the Bront&#279; siblings lived the longest?", "answer": "Charlotte", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "597cda61e347d002c297e4d4", "question": "What do deciduous trees do?", "answer": "Lose their leaves in winter", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff20f9c31a458464a93c435", "question": "Who wrote the novel \"The Yearling\"?", "answer": "Marjorie Kinnan Rawlings", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339164", "question": "Who directed \"Raiders of the Lost Ark\"?", "answer": "Steven Spielberg", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113398db", "question": "On what TV show did Amanda Blake play the role of saloon/brothel manager Miss Kitty Russell?", "answer": "Gunsmoke", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c13a", "question": "How many squares are there on a chessboard?", "answer": "64", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe93bce6bd93ce3a4e5f6a6", "question": "Percentage-wise, how big were the brains of the extinct species Australopithecus compared to a modern human brain?", "answer": "35%", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ff3c1bc4f032c0db195b478", "question": "What tribe of Native Americans was the first to encounter the Pilgrims?", "answer": "The Wampanoag", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5c3e9930ebfabb9c85d8a970", "question": "What film starred Rosie O'Donnell, Rita Wilson and Meg Ryan?", "answer": "Sleepless in Seattle", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae1c", "question": "How many battleships were sunk during the attack of Pearl Harbor?", "answer": "5", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cec", "question": "What Beatles song is set \"somewhere in the Black Mountain hills of Dakota\"?", "answer": "Rocky Raccoon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b240", "question": "What royal subject married Lisa Halaby?", "answer": "King Hussein of Jordan", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133955f", "question": "What is the sport in the movie \"The Hustler\"?", "answer": "Pool", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b717", "question": "What song's lyrics include \"tap, tap, tapping at your windowpane and bringing joy to every girl and boy\"?", "answer": "Suzy Snowflake", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b865", "question": "What is the only bird to be honored by its own year on the Chinese calendar?", "answer": "Rooster", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133990a", "question": "What band, formed in 1977, was fronted by singer/guitarist Mark Knopfler?", "answer": "Dire Straits", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b17", "question": "What was the first name of Julia Roberts' character in the 2001 movie \"Ocean's Eleven\"?", "answer": "Tess", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad43", "question": "Which country seized the USS Pueblo after accusing its American crew of unlawful spying in 1968?", "answer": "North Korea", "category": "history"}, {"id": "596df8ccf0cc2631d16a3c63", "question": "Crazy Horse and Sitting Bull were born in which US state?", "answer": "South Dakota", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b17b", "question": "What year did Montenegro declare its independence from Serbia and Montenegro?", "answer": "2006", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ae34", "question": "Who was the first US president to appear on television?", "answer": "Franklin D. Roosevelt", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c77", "question": "Who wrote the 1955 controversial novel \"Lolita\"?", "answer": "Vladamir Nabokov", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ac00", "question": "What is a native of Tangier called?", "answer": "Tangerian", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c6ea", "question": "In what part of a flower is pollen produced?", "answer": "Stamen", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b35f", "question": "Who was Tommy Lee Jones' upperclassman roommate at Harvard?", "answer": "Al Gore", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113394d6", "question": "Who was the first president of the Academy of Motion of Picture Arts and Sciences?", "answer": "Douglas Fairbanks Jr.", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f031133887e", "question": "Which character do the events of the narrative's plot revolve around and with whom the audience identifies itself with?", "answer": "The Protagonist", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338887", "question": "What is the singular of graffiti?", "answer": "Graffito", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f07", "question": "What author created the character of Father Brown?", "answer": "G. K. Chesterton", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fefbe856ce05a3942286ef2", "question": "Who recorded the song \"One of These Nights\"?", "answer": "Eagles", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5cefc100948005ec986edce2", "question": "Who is the ninth member of the group LOONA to debut?", "answer": "Yves", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b2ae", "question": "What nation was led by Theodoric the Great?", "answer": "The Ostrogoths", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133994a", "question": "Who played Spiderman's arch\u00ad-nemesis, Green Goblin, in the 2002 Spider- Man movie?", "answer": "Willem Dafoe", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fefbeb76ce05a3942286ef5", "question": "What famous singer was nicknamed \"Chairman of the Board\"?", "answer": "Frank Sinatra", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe76f5deec85e375820b2e8", "question": "Where is the world\u2019s largest jazz festival?", "answer": "Montreal", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339166", "question": "What is the secret identity of Don Vito Corleone?", "answer": "The Godfather", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5e8a68ef9a45431f553a9cd5", "question": "In modern physical cosmology, what notion states that the distribution of matter across the universe is approximately even?", "answer": "Cosmological principle", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5b3232eebf195a31e15d7395", "question": "What movie marked Jodie Foster's directorial debut?", "answer": "Little Man Tate", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391a1", "question": "Who is known as Slim Shady?", "answer": "Marshall Mathers", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b99a", "question": "What was the original name of the John F. Kennedy International Airport in New York?", "answer": "Idlewild Airport", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113389a9", "question": "Who considered founding a utopian art colony at Arles in France prior to his suicide?", "answer": "Vincent van Gogh", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fbae5750738315b1fb74e22", "question": "Who was the first football player drafted in 1936 during the first ever NFL draft?", "answer": "Jay Berwanger", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b82a", "question": "How many instruments accompany someone singing \"a cappella\"?", "answer": "None", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59029f62cad1ec93f27df75f", "question": "What is the thin layer of foam on top of an espresso called?", "answer": "Crema", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5df", "question": "What color is known as \"vert\" on a coat of arms?", "answer": "Green", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58f565ef33a95c66dc4fe75c", "question": "Bismarck is the capital of which US state?", "answer": "North Dakota", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a2a", "question": "What Blue Collar Comedy Tour comedian is known for his routine concerning \"Tater Salad\"?", "answer": "Ron White", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fec8d5cec223966ae8f8852", "question": "What is the name of the leader of the gang that often assaulted Andy in prison in the movie \"The Shawshank Redemption\"?", "answer": "Bogs", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af5e", "question": "Who created the first pair of stereo headphones in 1943?", "answer": "John C. Koss", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c386", "question": "Bronze is an alloy of what two metals?", "answer": "Tin and copper", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390be", "question": "What character is writer Colin Dexter most famous for creating?", "answer": "Inspector Morse", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ff213f431a458464a93c453", "question": "\"Occam\u2019s Razor\" posits that what kind of idea is usually most accurate?", "answer": "Simplest", "category": "general"}, {"id": "601b4bff49076251badbeacb", "question": "Which U.S. President had the most children?", "answer": "John Tyler -- The 10th president had 16 children \u2014 15 with his two wives and one born out of wedlock.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5904a106cf93664eb10486bc", "question": "The \"Bodansky Unit\", now an obsolete unit, used to measure the concentration of what in the blood stream?", "answer": "Alkaline phosphatase", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b00a", "question": "What region was explored by Juan Rodriguez Cabrillo?", "answer": "California", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c728", "question": "Who was the first man to return safely from space?", "answer": "Yuri Gagarin", "category": "science"}, {"id": "594d057b1a1c922dd1ac64a2", "question": "What is Ronald Biggs famous for?", "answer": "Being one of the \"Great Train Robbers\"", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe69d1d20565ad31a57c775", "question": "How many U.S. states sit on land bought by the Louisiana Purchase?", "answer": "15", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b145", "question": "What was the name for the German mercenaries who fought against the American rebels during the Revolutionary War?", "answer": "Hessians", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd66216a5bfecdd737e0841", "question": "Who was on the first cover of \"Rolling Stone\"?", "answer": "John Lennon", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe3e80338e4e5d4832e6309", "question": "Approximately, how much money did U.S. children spend on war bonds as part of the World War II effort?", "answer": "$1 billion", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e5f", "question": "According to the poem, how many spectators saw Mighty Casey strike out?", "answer": "Five thousand", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fea7af1ff048f679a45abf0", "question": "Masses are to Newton's Gravitational Law as charges are to what?", "answer": "Coulomb's Law", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339521", "question": "The line \"Heeere's Johnny!\" comes from which movie?", "answer": "The Shining", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5de65a4cf89b9ec3da2d335e", "question": "Who played Bruce Wayne in the 1989 film \"Batman\"?", "answer": "Michael Keaton", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59067a93ff9c0647b50a805b", "question": "What date did the United Kingdom European Union membership referendum took place on?", "answer": "June 23, 2016", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bb6f", "question": "What American company marketed the first home video game console \u00adthe Odyssey \u00adin 1972?", "answer": "Magnavox", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f66", "question": "What is \"bountiful mother\" in Latin?", "answer": "Alma mater", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ffa3cf7c73aa70ea0b70af1", "question": "Where will you find the Beagle Channel?", "answer": "In Tierra del Fuego Archipelago on the southern tip of South America between Chile and Argentina.", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a108", "question": "In the film \"American Hot Wax\", who did Jay Leno play?", "answer": "Mookie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5bb35b4f2627b8fe95581beb", "question": "In ABC's \"Once Upon a Time\" what character was played by Colin O' Donoghue?", "answer": "Captain Hook", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bde8", "question": "Who invented the method he called \"rope-a-dope\"?", "answer": "Muhammad Ali", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338897", "question": "What drug did Sherlock Holmes take at the start of his career?", "answer": "Cocaine", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba89", "question": "In what year did the NBA introduce the 24 \u00adsecond shot clock?", "answer": "1954", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338f59", "question": "What famous clipper ship took its name from Scots words for \"short shirt\" in a Robert Burns poem?", "answer": "The Cutty Sark", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe3e58738e4e5d4832e6304", "question": "What is the collective name for household deities worshiped by the Romans?", "answer": "Lares", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113389e8", "question": "What surname for John in \"The Importance of Being Earnest\" did Oscar Wilde take from the seaside town he vacationed at?", "answer": "Worthing", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fecdad4ec223966ae8f88ec", "question": "In what movie did Sidney Poitier say, \"They call me Mister Tibbs\"?", "answer": "\"In the Heat of the Night\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6e5", "question": "What sport has its name abbreviated to BMX?", "answer": "Bicycle Moto-cross", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bb7c", "question": "What brand of breakfast cereal has the phrase \"Two Scoops!\" emblazoned on its box?", "answer": "Kellogg's Raisin Bran", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a681", "question": "What lake is located between Lake Huron and Lake Erie?", "answer": "Lake St. Clair", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fd6a1736c0f9723ab15cb39", "question": "The Ishtar Gate was the main entrance to which ancient city?", "answer": "Babylon", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb12", "question": "In what year did Jimmy Buffett open his first Margaritaville restaurant?", "answer": "1985", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fc1", "question": "What genre is Iggy Pop considered to be the grandfather of?", "answer": "Punk", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aea0", "question": "Which Edward was the first ever Prince of Wales?", "answer": "Edward II", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe7c7c1877e98cb977789d6", "question": "Where are the Whitsunday Islands located?", "answer": "Australia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339735", "question": "In which decade was the first electric guitar made?", "answer": "1930s", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "58d47441f8e329de4f87789b", "question": "The Bunya Pine tree is native to which country?", "answer": "Australia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff20e6631a458464a93c421", "question": "First published in 1842, \"The Masque of the Red Death\" is a short story by which American writer?", "answer": "Edgar Allan Poe", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cace", "question": "What is heliology the study of?", "answer": "The Sun", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b64e", "question": "What media personality was once a speechwriter for Richard Nixon?", "answer": "Ben Stein", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6010c5370775fa611bce67c4", "question": "What newspaper is nicknamed \"the Gray Lady\"?", "answer": "The New York Times", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe7bd35877e98cb97778956", "question": "What African country served as the setting for Tatooine in Star Wars?", "answer": "Tunisia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b59c", "question": "Who was the first deaf Miss America, crowned in 1995?", "answer": "Heather Whitestone", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fea3281ff048f679a45aae7", "question": "How many patents did Thomas Edison accumulate during his lifetime?", "answer": "2332 worldwide (1,093 in the US)", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fedd8656ce05a3942286d6e", "question": "Which player was selected first in the 1983 NBA Draft?", "answer": "Ralph Sampson", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5909d1a4bb53d1af65886503", "question": "Who wrote the 1958 book \"Journey to Christmas\"?", "answer": "B. J. Chute", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396c6", "question": "Who voiced the character of Woody in the Toy Story movie series?", "answer": "Tom Hanks", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bb68", "question": "What pharmaceutical company manufactures the drug Viagra?", "answer": "Pfizer", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59071c123745b36be73039c7", "question": "Who is Tony\u2019s fraternal twin in the comic series \"Chew\"?", "answer": "Antonelle Chu", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "6015de8bfe83fe1f2a824b6d", "question": "What general during the American Revolutionary War fought for the American Continental Army but defected to the British Army?", "answer": "Benedict Arnold", "category": "history"}, {"id": "60078197bd51d85e222ab64d", "question": "In 1908, what American artist painted elaborate murals in the newly completed Pennsylvania State Capitol Building?", "answer": "Edwin Austin Abbey\u00a0began an ambitious program of murals and other artworks for the newly completed Pennsylvania State Capitol.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "600399bb57a0e35c43f8389f", "question": "What German artist had Emperor Rudolph II as a patron?", "answer": "Hans von Aachen\u00a0-- He was one of the leading painters of Northern Mannerism and a painter of princely and\u00a0 aristocratic portraits.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fd82212d0de9af39e9d46a8", "question": "Who was the last Roman Emperor?", "answer": "Romulus Augustulus", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5febb97d7e83c707845b2139", "question": "What do mercury and bromine have in common?", "answer": "They are liquid at room temperature", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6ef", "question": "Which US state is home to Joshua Tree National Park?", "answer": "California", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133acdd", "question": "What connection did Thomas Edison have with the construction of Yankee Stadium?", "answer": "His company made the cement", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5dc", "question": "Which champagne company took over the perfume of the Givenchy fashion house in 1981?", "answer": "Veuve Clicquot", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133936b", "question": "How many Oscar nominations did the 2002 movie \"Chicago\" receive?", "answer": "Thirteen", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399fc", "question": "What 1992 film features the characters Colonel Nathan Jessup and Lieutenant Daniel Kaffee?", "answer": "A Few Good Men", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a926", "question": "What city is threatened by the effects of acqua alta?", "answer": "Venice", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9cf", "question": "What is the capital of the US state New Jersey?", "answer": "Trenton", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392fd", "question": "In the movie \"The Karate Kid\", what is the name of Daniel's master?", "answer": "Mr. Miyagi", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b59f", "question": "What does the \"Big Mac Index\" measure?", "answer": "Purchasing power parity between two currencies", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391cd", "question": "Who directed the movie \"Alien\"?", "answer": "Ridley Scott", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c049", "question": "Which bird is the national bird of Argentina?", "answer": "Rufous Hornero", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339825", "question": "What quintet featured Danny, Donnie, Joe, Jonathan and Jordan?", "answer": "New Kids on the Block", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133921b", "question": "What instrument did Sting play with the band \"The Police\"?", "answer": "Bass guitar", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fefa6196ce05a3942286eca", "question": "In which city does the film \"Home Alone\" take place?", "answer": "Chicago", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6015de62fe83fe1f2a824b69", "question": "What Spartan king led a small army of 300 Spartans against a vastly superior Persian force in the Battle of Thermopylae?", "answer": "Leonidas, King of Sparta", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b42", "question": "In what movie did Tom Cruise play real-life character Ron Kovic?", "answer": "Born on the 4 th of July", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ab99c6121a8909e5c332d35", "question": "Which band released the album \"Breakfast in America\"?", "answer": "Supertramp", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b3c7", "question": "US President James Garfield died of what cause?", "answer": "He was shot", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6a9", "question": "What traditional Russian instrument looks like a triangular guitar?", "answer": "The balalaika", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5feccd95ec223966ae8f88ac", "question": "In \"Deadpool\", Wade Wilson teams up with Colossus and what other member of the X-men?", "answer": "Negasonic Teenage Warhead", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339814", "question": "\"Take the A Train\" was the signature tune of whose band?", "answer": "Duke Ellington", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff6719552a821ff76ae8b24", "question": "What manufacturer introduced \"Pringles\" potato chips in 1967?", "answer": "Procter & Gamble", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338dab", "question": "Who satirized the threat of nuclear was in \"The Butter Battle Book\"?", "answer": "Dr. Seuss", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a28b", "question": "Who is the lead singer of Metallica?", "answer": "James Hetfield", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "597ddd3077980686f722d17c", "question": "When was the first permanent photograph taken?", "answer": "1826", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5ffa3d02c73aa70ea0b70af2", "question": "Which two countries have a longstanding dispute over the granite islet of Rockall?", "answer": "Scotland and Ireland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fdffbdd1cf6db9ac4808cf9", "question": "What is the only country capital that contains a national park?", "answer": "Nairobi, Kenya", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391b6", "question": "Which movie popularized the phrase \"You had me at hello.\"?", "answer": "Jerry Maguire", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fecdd3eec223966ae8f8902", "question": "Who is the godmother of Kurt Cobain and Courtney Love's kid Francis Bean?", "answer": "Drew Barrymore", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ffa3a1cc73aa70ea0b70add", "question": "Toronto is on the shores of which Great Lake?", "answer": "Ontario", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "6008df6cf4f3bc4a292f862a", "question": "What did Zacchaeus do in order to catch a glimpse at Jesus Christ?", "answer": "Zacchaeus climbed a tree so he could have clear view of the Messiah on his way to Jericho.", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a092", "question": "Who sang \"That's Alright Mama\"?", "answer": "Elvis Presley", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1d9", "question": "What is Merlin's owl name in Disney's film \"The Sword in the Stone\"?", "answer": "Archimedes", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59a552183e1c6f9840ba3192", "question": "In Greek mythology, what were Medusa, Stheno and Euryale collectively known as?", "answer": "The Gorgons", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338dd9", "question": "From what language did English borrow the word \"luau\"?", "answer": "Hawaiian", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338eb5", "question": "What Broadway musical featured the song \"Buenos Aires\"?", "answer": "Evita", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "59523e9a736d4be723796b51", "question": "What is Toronto\u2019s Pearson International Airport code?", "answer": "YYZ", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339d5b", "question": "The shoe-obsessed Spats Colombo is the villain of what 1959 comedy?", "answer": "Some Like It Hot", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5904998ccf93664eb1048692", "question": "Which famous actor is honored with a statue in Leicester Square?", "answer": "Charlie Chaplin", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c40", "question": "Who wrote the famous poem \"The Waste Land\"?", "answer": "T.S. Elliot", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a5ae", "question": "What is the capitol of Morocco?", "answer": "Rabat", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe7c1cc877e98cb9777897d", "question": "What does Salzburg translate to?", "answer": "Salt Castle", "category": "geography"}]